Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
THE TANK
SOVIET UNION, DNIEPER FRONT, AUTUMN 1943.
EIGHT MONTHS AFTER STALINGRAD,
THE GERMAN ARMY IS IN RETREAT.
Withdraw!
Go! Go! Go! Move!
- Take up position behind the bridge.
- Faster!
Hurry!
Retreat!
Fall back!
- Second unit, cross the bridge!
- Move!
Commander, our troops have retreated.
Lieutenant. Should we retreat, too?
Lieutenant!
Keilig, any enemy radio?
There they are.
Soviet T-34s. I see them!
- 600. On target!
- Ready for firing.
Give the order, Lieutenant.
Philip!
Philip.
- Fire.
- Achtung!
Hit. Destroyed.
Loaded!
- Infantry between!
- Machine Gun, fire!
To the right! More tanks.
- On target.
- Fire!
Achtung!
Hit.
- Destroyed.
- Loaded!
Fire MG! Keep on them!
We've destroyed the two in the front
and blocked the way.
- Let's get out of here!
- Fire!
Achtung!
Philip, did you hear me?
We can avoid them.
- Fire!
- Achtung!
- Loaded.
- More keep coming.
- We're blowing up the bridge at midnight.
- In five minutes.
We've still got time. Fire!
Achtung!
We need to move. Now!
- We've got four and a half minutes.
- The bridge is 600 meters long.
Anti-tank gun, twelve o'clock!
- I have to reload.
- Fire!
I've got it.
Achtung!
Loaded.
We're alone and out of time, Philip.
Give the order.
Give the order, Philip!
Retreat. Hummel, back across the bridge.
Yes, Commander.
Go, go, go!
Go, Hummel!
Go! Four minutes left. Four minutes!
Faster, Hummel.
We won't make it!
They're not following us anymore.
And they've stopped firing.
- They must know we're going to blow it up.
- We'll make it.
- Ilyushins!
- They can't harm us.
- Commander...
- Fire!
It's getting in. Fire's getting in!
I'm on fire! I'm on fire!
Move, Helmut, move!
Fire!
Go, Helmut! Keep going. Go!
Move, Helmut!
Hit it!
I think we're going to make it, Philip!
We're going to make it!
We're alone and out of time, Philip.
Give the order.
Ilyushins!
I'm on fire! I'm on fire!
PERVITIN
AMPHETAMINES
When do we get there?
CLASSIFIED
24TH TANK CORPS
ORDER FOR EXECUTION
OF OPERATION LABYRINTH
INDIVIDUAL ORDER:
LIEUTENANT GERKENS, 3RD COMPANY...
Unescorted...
BRING COL. VON HARDENBURG
WITH CLASSIFIED DOCUMENTS BACK TO HQ...
Paul?
Give me a hand.
Turn it on.
Pass it up.
Lieutenant.
Welcome back.
- Thanks, Christian.
- Men!
Lieutenant.
Boss.
How's our Tiger?
Battered and bruised.
But ready for action.
Good.
And you?
Same. A few scrapes and burns.
Nothing too serious.
New orders?
Unfortunately, yes.
Colonel Richter
wants us to move out today.
- And what about our leave?
- Cancelled.
Today?
Today.
Where to?
Back to the east. Over the Psel.
- To Ivan country?
- In between.
Into no-man's land.
Our orders are to locate the whereabouts
of Colonel von Hardenburg
and to bring him back.
Von Hardenburg? I thought he was dead.
I thought so too.
But many probably think we are too.
- Which unit will accompany us?
- None.
The order is top secret.
He's presumably in one of our bunker
complexes east of Novyi Yar.
Shit.
- Why us?
- Orders are orders.
If we'd needed to know,
they'd have told us.
But a single Tiger tank...
They must believe
if someone can do it, we can.
Get the tank ready.
Let's go, men.
Let's go.
Wolf to Fox's Den,
we're off to the labyrinth for 48 hours.
Wolf over and out.
Helmut.
Give me a light!
Greatest tank ever built
and the driver can't stick his head out
or see anything.
And you assholes
get the sun on your faces.
The builders knew what ugly bastards
you drivers are!
Von Hardenburg?
But he stayed in Stalingrad
with the Sixth after we were pulled out.
A miracle he survived the fighting.
I heard he cut off his own hand.
I heard that, too.
He was buried
under the tractor factory rubble.
His hand was trapped.
After five days,
he had to cut it off with a knife.
To survive.
I told you.
Helmut, I still have your lighter.
But it's mine now.
If he survived, he must be a Russian spy.
That must be why they want him back.
Apparently he crawled out of the rubble
and a young lady
took pity on him and hid him.
Later, he made his way back to our side
disguised as a farmer.
And they sent his ass back to the front
with just one hand?
I almost feel sorry for him.
Now they're sending our asses
after him to bring him back.
Sounds even more like a Russian spy.
Field officers, all one-handed artists.
What makes him so important?
The "von" in his name?
The mission order says he was working
on a secret disengagement plan.
It contains all our positions,
radio codes and weapons supplies.
If it falls into Russian hands,
the gates to the Reich will be wide open.
Our mission has the code name
Operation Labyrinth.
Didn't they try to reach him by radio?
He hasn't answered
since we blew up the bridge.
In Stalingrad...
Those were his orders, right?
He was the commanding officer, yes.
What you got there, squirt?
No one-handed shenanigans in my tank!
I wasn't doing anything.
I clearly saw it.
Five kilometers to the front.
Keep your eyes peeled after that.
- Weller, what's all that about?
- Probably to confuse the Russians.
Looks like the plan's to retreat further.
I thought Adolf the Austrian
didn't believe in retreat.
One of yours, Weller.
- Not the kind I know.
- You on your Tyrolean pig farm.
First of all, it's not a pig farm.
It's a vineyard.
And it's the Wachau.
The most beautiful place in the world.
- Wachau!
- Keilig, anything on the radio?
All I'm getting is static.
Maybe that's better.
Then Ivan can't listen in.
Hummel, we'll leave the road in 50 meters.
45 degrees to the left,
away from the open field.
- I want to be in cover by nightfall.
- Yes, Sir!
Drink up and put out the fire.
You and I will take first watch, Michel.
Are there partisans around?
You never know.
Better keep our eyes and ears open.
Bodhana always said...
these woods are full of ghosts.
Who's Bodhana?
A peasant girl he met back in Tolokonnoye.
She sold us milk and eggs.
- And the clap too, right, squirt?
- Helmut!
- I didn't sleep with her.
- But you would've liked to.
Listen to Uncle Helmut, squirt.
A moment of fun, a lifetime of regret.
And she said these woods
are full of ghosts?
Yes, that the souls of the dead
roam those woods.
The Ukrainians believe that.
So do lots of people back home in Silesia.
Silesia's just one big pig farm.
Why didn't we burn to death, Lieutenant?
On the bridge.
We only made it because I kept
my foot on the gas till the end.
Even though it was on fire.
You all owe me a new pair of boots.
You know von Hardenburg well,
don't you, Lieutenant?
We went to military academy together.
You were friends?
Yes, but that was long ago.
Is it true that he's your son's godfather?
Enough for now. Go sleep.
Will-o'-the-wisp.
Don't let Hummel get to you.
He's got it in for me.
He lost his son.
He was only 15.
He manned the Humboldthain Flak tower
during an air raid.
It was a direct hit.
Hummel had to bury an empty coffin.
Maybe it's his way of showing you
you matter to him.
Get some rest.
I'll take over the watch.
Philip.
What do you hear?
Out with it. What do you hear?
It's Latin.
Listen to this.
"Lamb of God, have mercy on us."
"Lamb of God, who takes away the sins..."
"Lamb of God, give us eternal rest."
It's mass.
- It's always on the radio at home too.
- They're Orthodox here.
Why would they listen to a Latin mass?
Anti-tank barriers. Stay on the right.
Ivan probably wants to shake us.
Turn off that hocus-pocus.
Who built that?
We did. Or rather what was left
of Zhukov's army after we captured them.
Those who were too weak
are buried under that.
Hummel, there's a gap in the barrier.
We'll go through it. Left stick.
Tank halt!
- What is it?
- Mines!
- Engine off.
- Shit.
What do we do now?
Michel, Keilig, down.
We have to search the ground.
Careful. Jump onto our own tracks.
Thoroughly!
Shit. Michel!
Come here.
It's too close to the tread.
We'll have to dig it out.
You'll help me. Keilig!
Check the ground next to our tracks
in case we need to back up.
- Yes, Sir!
- Lieutenant.
Nine o'clock. 3,000 meters.
Dust on the horizon.
- Could be an ambush.
- Keep an eye on it, Christian.
Help me.
There.
Clear the earth from underneath the mine
so we can lift it up.
I'll try to unscrew the detonator. Go on.
Careful.
Damn, I can't see anything.
We have to lift it.
Carefully.
- Lieutenant!
- What?
Something moved. I'm holding it.
It feels like a hand grenade.
It's true.
Bastards. They took the safety pins out.
It's a double booby trap.
If you move your hands,
the grenade will move
and activate the detonator
and both of us will blow up with the mine.
You need to keep calm, Michel.
Michel!
Michel.
Here.
Breathe.
Good.
Yes, Sir.
- Weller, what's the status?
- Vehicles seem to be moving away.
Prepare to backtrack!
What's going on?
First I'll move them to safety,
then I'll come back for you.
Understood?
Understood.
Unknown vehicles
at five to six kilometers.
Moving away.
- Hummel!
- Where's Michel?
Slowly reverse the Tiger
on our old tracks.
- Where's Michel?
- The Tiger is our priority.
Start moving!
Straight.
Jesus fucking Christ! The little squirt.
Straight, I said!
Halt!
Rope.
- You're doing great, Michel! Really great.
- Jesus fucking Christ.
I'm going to get you...
home safely.
Careful!
Now listen to me carefully, Michel.
Look at me.
You're going to slowly slide
your hand out, little by little.
So that the weight of the mine
presses down on the grenade's detonator.
Go.
Slowly.
Keep moving, slowly.
Slower.
Very good, Michel. Very good.
Keep going.
Slowly.
Carefully.
Keep going. Good.
Careful.
Get up.
Come on.
Everyone down.
Get behind the tank!
This one is yours.
- You've got nerves of steel.
- Mount up.
Great job.
You'll get no hugs from me, squirt.
But I'll let you hang that picture
of your girlfriend up in my tank.
Hummel, sharp left!
Halt!
Tank at twelve o'clock.
Backwards. Start moving!
Sharp left. Hurry!
Smoke grenades.
Straight!
Hummel, we need more distance.
Out of the woods. Step on it!
And halt!
That was a heavy caliber tank.
SU-100, I'd guess.
Tank Killer.
One hit with his shot and we're finished.
Lieutenant.
More are coming.
At least three more tanks.
We'll avoid them.
We can stay here
and take them on one by one.
There are too many.
We can't jeopardize the mission!
We're stuck between them and the river.
Attacking is our only chance.
They've got us trapped.
The river!
We've got a chance.
Reverse. Then east, three o'clock.
Halt.
Engine off.
Philip, what are you doing?
Everyone out.
What the hell?
Move!
Prepare the tank to dive.
- What?
- The Tiger is built to dive.
- We've only done that in training.
- Move!
Never in combat!
Seems like the right time to do so.
We've taken several bad hits.
We might sink like a stone.
You repaired it, and I trust you.
Get moving.
Move! Go, go, go!
Perfect.
Everyone inside.
Hummel, start engine.
WATER DRIVE
Start moving! Out of here.
CLOSE
Submerging.
Hummel, stop.
It feels really loud.
- Can't we turn off the engine?
- No.
- If it doesn't restart, you'll drown here.
But they can see our exhaust. Engine off!
What? If it doesn't restart, we're goners.
Off.
What's the situation?
Holding tight for now.
Here too.
No water to report.
How long can we stay underwater?
Engine sounds.
They're coming closer.
Burning in a tank is one thing.
But drowning...
Weller was right.
We should have faced them in the field.
- We're sitting ducks!
- Quiet.
We'll stay submerged
to be on the safe side.
How long do you want to wait?
Until I'm sure we're not
walking into a trap once we emerge.
Keilig, what time have you got?
Nearly 12,
but it's stopped since the bridge.
Bodhana told me
there's a merman in the lakes.
He pulls you down into the deep
when you go swimming.
What a cheery soul, your "Spatzl."
- Huh?
- Shut up!
Right now.
Philip!
- Lieutenant!
- Shit, we're leaking!
We need to surface,
whether they're there or not.
All right. We'll cross the river
and surface on the other side.
- Cross the river?
- They could still be nearby.
It's safer. And not looking for a bridge
will save us fuel.
Helmut! Start the engine!
Shit.
Again! Again!
Go on! Go on, Hummel!
Come on, Helmut! Again!
Yes!
Helmut, start moving!
If we get stuck down here, we won't even
be able to get our hatches open.
- I can't swim.
- I can't either.
We won't need to either,
we'll die in an iron coffin.
Halt, engine off.
Nothing in sight. Everyone out.
Let's get our little Tiger ready again.
We only have enough fuel
for 20 kilometers.
- Yeah.
Shit.
What?
Ivan owes me a new one.
That was close.
Come on. We've got a mission to complete.
Better take your tank candy.
It's going to be a long night.
And I want you to stay wide awake.
I'd rather keep a clear head.
Halt.
Engine off.
What's going on?
They're ours.
Start engine. Keep moving.
Engine off. Dismount.
Move it! Down!
Heil Hitler.
Tank boys.
Go on! Faster.
Hurry up!
Hurry up, men.
The horses too!
Lieutenant Gerkens,
Heavy Tank Battalion 503.
Requesting fuel.
Lieutenant Colonel Krebs.
What happened? Took a wrong turn?
Special mission.
You tank boys, always special!
I was told we didn't have
any more troops here.
This is our special mission.
Cleaning up all the villages
that helped the partisans.
Move! Move!
You're sending them to work camps?
The time for work camps is long over.
We lock the door.
When we set it on fire,
their animals kick them to death.
Saves ammunition.
Our little contribution
to the great cause.
The Reich's hunger for death is so great
that it can't produce enough ammunition.
It looks like we're almost done here.
Pack it up, men.
You remember the flames, don't you?
So, my work here is done.
Oh, and as for your fuel...
Move out!
Let's get out of here right away.
We'll sleep in the Tiger tonight.
Move out!
Philip.
To hell with that.
Michel, give me something stronger!
More.
Nectar of the Gods.
I thought you were a winemaker.
Even a simple Latin teacher like me
knows it's complete piss.
'37 Baron von Claussen.
Emerald Grüner Veltliner.
Best vintage I ever made.
Subtle fruit
with carefully balanced acidity and...
delicate apricot notes.
We called it "Nectar of the Gods."
Marshal Göring liked it so much
he bought half the vintage.
And now all that's left of it...
is a memory.
And I have no choice
but to drink this piss.
Piss or not,
it does what it's meant to do.
Lieutenant?
How does an Austrian peasant learn
to make wine fit for the Reichsmarschall?
In the Wachau.
Winemaking's in our blood.
My father taught me,
and his father taught him.
If you made the wine,
who is this Baron von Claussen?
I was his winemaker.
Well, then it's your wine.
His land, his grapes.
His sun, his wind, his rain?
For an old Latin teacher,
you sure sound like a Red again, Keilig.
If the ancient Romans
handed down one thing to us,
if they made one great contribution
to human knowledge, it's war.
They waged it eternally.
To subjugate their own people,
not the enemy.
Keep fighting, keep waging war,
never any peace.
So the Latin teacher, the winemaker,
the train driver and the farm boy join in.
There's no choice. "Yes, Sir. No, Sir."
Orders must be followed.
Forget who you were
and what you once loved.
We follow orders
to protect the people we love.
Orders are the only thing we have.
Without them, everything falls apart.
The army, society, everything.
No place for politics in my tank!
Besides, you're wrong.
The ancient Romans
didn't have train drivers.
Even I know that.
And you don't know much.
Hey. Shut up!
To the train drivers!
The saviors of society!
Weller. Lighter.
I don't know what you mean.
I wish I could forget.
Forget who we once were.
It'll never be like it used to be.
How can it be?
After all this.
Who we once were?
We're still the same.
We followed orders.
And we did what was demanded of us.
That's all.
When all of this is over, then...
visit me in Austria
and I'll show you my vineyard.
And we'll drink a bottle together.
We'll do that.
Halt!
What is it?
I don't like this.
Let's keep our distance.
The bunker's straight behind it
and we can't afford to take a detour.
Ready for combat.
Range?
1,000.
Helmut, pass the mill on the left side,
but slowly.
- On target.
- Start moving.
Must have been used for target practice.
We're entering range.
Keilig, MG!
Fire at will.
Damn sun! Keep your eyes peeled!
Halt! Gunfire at one o'clock!
Hummel, back up now! Move, move!
Weller, return fire.
That was close!
- Hummel, keep moving.
- Yes, Sir!
Keilig, fire MG!
Out of the line of fire! To the left!
Faster, Hummel!
Halt!
Weller, next to the mill sail.
Where it's collapsed. 900.
Identified.
- On target.
- Unlocked!
Fire!
Nothing in sight. Hit doubtful.
What?
An SU-100.
- Is it the same one?
- What the...
This can't be. What the hell?
- Must've followed us.
- That's impossible!
Avoid him, Hummel.
Keilig, keep him covered.
Start moving! Fire!
- Fire!
- Achtung!
It ricocheted off.
The armor is far too strong.
Loaded!
More distance.
We have to get them from the side.
- Shit!
- That was the exhaust pipe!
- Damn it!
- Reverse, full speed, Hummel.
Smoke grenades.
Where are you?
- Pierced clean through!
- You okay?
- Yes.
- It's turning around.
Shit!
Philip, they're too strong!
Yes, but it's just a giant gun on chains.
We're faster, more agile.
They have to turn the whole tank to fire.
Hummel, move forward slowly.
Left stick. I want to offer him our flank.
- What about our flank?
- Trust me.
Move!
Gun to three o'clock.
We'll be right in their barrel.
Keep your nerve!
Lieutenant!
Keep your nerve.
The Russians will have us soon.
MG! Distract them.
Halt!
Come on, Philip!
- On target!
- Hold.
I've got him.
Hold.
Stop MG.
- Fire.
- Achtung!
Hit. Destroyed.
The problem with those tanks is
they can't see
what's right in front of them.
We should've attacked them in the woods!
That damn tank nearly destroyed us!
Keilig?
- Keilig, you all right?
- Keilig!
- Keilig...
- Keilig, you bastard!
- Lieutenant!
- Are you hit, Keilig?
Shrapnel.
My lungs.
Shit!
Take me into the sun.
Lay him on the roof.
Take his legs.
Careful.
It's all okay, Keilig. It's okay.
You and Hardenburg...
it's personal, isn't it?
Try not to talk.
Write...
Write to Luise and the girls.
I'll do that. I promise.
I wanted to teach again.
In '39 I had...
a senior class.
One of the loveliest summers.
After that...
there was only war.
I...
Keilig.
Let's check the Tiger.
We can patch this one up, but...
Lieutenant!
What?
Damn.
Bodies don't burn that fast.
Enough.
We go back to base and tell them
we didn't find von Hardenburg.
Something's not right here.
It's only another 20 kilometers.
Our exhaust pipe is shot.
We can repair it, with parts from the SU.
We only have fuel for 30 kilometers.
- That won't even get us back!
- There'll be supplies in the bunker.
I hope von Hardenburg is worth all this.
But if he's a spy, I'll put a bullet
through his head myself.
To work.
Move.
You remember the flames, don't you?
Lieutenant?
Keil...
Michel, check the radio.
Lieutenant.
Turn it off.
Off!
How much longer?
How long do you want to keep going?
Until we've found him
and brought him home.
Home?
It isn't a home.
They're just our fucking lines.
Until we retreat to the next lines.
And then to the next and the next!
Why is von Hardenburg so important?
Are they afraid he'll defect?
Maybe Keilig was right.
That he already has and we're...
walking into a trap.
Or is he only important to you?
Keilig was right.
He said it was personal
between you and von Hardenburg.
Why are you dragging us into it?
- Why?
- They're orders.
If the Russians find him, they'll have
our positions, frequencies, tactics...
Then the gates to the Reich
will be wide open. I know, Philip!
But we're wide open to attack too!
The enemy knows we're here.
Philip! Don't you get that?
Please wake up!
I think you've taken unnecessary risks.
And you've been compromised.
I vote to relieve you
of command until we get back.
All right.
All of you decide.
Now.
Michel?
I'm with the Lieutenant.
Helmut?
You're the driver.
This is your tank.
You've been with us since Barbarossa.
I mean... Keilig's dead.
Exactly.
And... on the bridge and while diving,
you took risks.
I'm sorry.
Weller...
I'm with the Commander.
We won't speak of this again.
According to the map, there's an old path
to the forest where the bunker is.
Seems to be 45 degrees
to the left, Hummel.
Philip.
Tank halt!
What?
Footprints. Everyone dismount.
Michel!
Weapons ready.
Boot prints.
German made.
Load.
Michel, stop!
Booby trap.
Also German made.
The bunker must be very close.
Ready to fire.
- What the hell?
- Paratroopers.
They probably sent us
because they didn't manage it.
Let's go.
Come on in. Come on!
Lieutenant.
We're looking for Colonel von Hardenburg.
Of course.
He's in the command bunker
and has been expecting you.
I'll take you to him.
But if you want to linger a while...
I'm certain...
that we can entertain you well enough.
Maria, get these gentlemen
wine and something to eat.
You look like you've had a long journey.
To life!
Now take me to Colonel von Hardenburg.
Gladly, Lieutenant.
Well, then...
follow me.
But just you.
Come along.
Don't be afraid.
Lieutenant.
New order via radio message.
Cover withdrawal of the last forces
on the Dnieper bridge
before it gets blown up.
Quite a labyrinth.
Be brave.
Paul.
So the stories are true then.
Germany lost a lot in Stalingrad.
What's one small hand in comparison?
Join me by the fire.
Your lance corporal told me
that you were expecting someone.
No. I wasn't expecting someone.
I was expecting you.
Then you're sure to know
I'm here to bring you back.
Certainly.
You had to make this journey.
I was your best friend.
Remember the summer
at the military academy in Hannover?
That warm August evening
when I introduced Marion to you?
We went swimming the next day.
Over to the little wooded island
in the middle of the lake.
It was a magical summer.
The best summer ever.
After that there was only war.
We have to go.
I assume you came in your Tiger.
- Yes.
- It's cramped in there.
Odd that they sent you in that
to pick us all up, don't you agree?
I'm sure they have their reasons.
And if I refuse?
I want to avoid it coming to that.
But if it should come to that...
then they sent just the right man,
didn't they?
Orders are orders, after all.
Come on, Philip. Eat with me.
A "last supper," so to speak.
We have no time for that.
- We have to go.
- No time for an old friend?
I'm your son's godfather.
You have me to thank for your happiness.
Sit down.
When you've been buried under rubble
for five days
and are slowly dying of thirst,
you have lots of time to think.
You see many things.
In the shadows.
I heard about your rescue.
Remarkable.
What did we do in Stalingrad, Philip?
I don't have time for your games.
What did we do in Stalingrad?
Paul, these are orders.
They come straight from division.
Sir, the other commanders
are getting nervous.
Some say that the enemy has a fix on them.
They want to know what to do.
Reports indicate women and children
sheltering inside.
But it's also full of Russian forces,
who control the factory,
and with it this part of the city.
Our assault will fail if we don't act now.
- Can you hear anything?
- No.
Paul...
these are orders, it's not our decision.
Is that so?
The other commanders are waiting.
Paul!
Man your positions, men! Ready to engage!
Pass on the order.
All other tanks, fire at will.
All tanks, fire at will!
Fire!
That wasn't our decision.
We had no choice. We had orders.
Yes, that may be.
But we had the responsibility.
It's midnight.
You have to get back over the Dnieper.
I'm here because of you.
We're all here because of you.
Don't you see that?
I'm here for Operation Labyrinth.
Operation Labyrinth?
- That's you!
- Philip!
I'm supposed to guide you out.
I'm here because...
- Colonel Richter sent me here.
- Who might he be?
Colonel Richter? Did he ever really exist?
Yes. The signs, they were there all along.
Keilig, what time have you got?
Nearly 12,
but it's stopped since the bridge.
- Bodies don't burn that fast.
- Something's not right here.
You remember the flames, don't you?
Why didn't we burn to death on the bridge?
Please wake up!
But Krebs...
- He...
- Maybe he was just a part of you.
Like all of us.
Philip!
It's midnight.
You have to get back over the Dnieper!
Philip! Give the order!
Why did you delay the order to retreat?
It's so unlike you
to put your crew and yourself in danger.
- Yes.
- Lieutenant?
Yes, it's been there all along.
The telegram informing you
that Marion and your son Fritz
died in Hamburg.
When the air raid began on July 24th,
they sought shelter
in the Church of St. Nicholas.
But when the bombs fell,
they died in the firestorm.
Fire!
I fought in this war to protect them.
We reap what we sow.
You led me here.
Where is here?
What's going on?
Paul, what's going on here?
What's going on here?
We've reached the end of your journey.
Mine ended back then.
That tractor factory, I never left it.
Come on, old friend.
It's time.
I have to get to my men, Paul.
They won't survive without me.
- Go, go, go!
- I'm on fire!
Move!
Helmut, go!
I'm on fire!
Go, go!
Where am I, Paul?
Where am I?